How could you date
談戀愛
in other's billiards hall?
跑人檯球廳談來了
You even broke the door.
還撬門
Your boss gave me the key.
你們老闆給的我鑰匙
It's indeed the same.
還真是一樣的
Who are you?
你誰啊
Lu Chen.
路晨
Are you the EOD expert of the Lu family?
你是路家那個排爆專家
I'm a SWAT.
特警
I know.
我知道 我知道
You usually dismantle the bombs.
你拆彈的
Why are you here in the middle of the night?
你大半夜來這兒
Is something wrong?
有情況啊
Your boss
你們老闆
asked me to check
讓我來檢查一下
the surveillance system here.
這邊的監控系統
He said there were blind spots
說有死角拍不到
and asked me to adjust
讓我來調整一下
the angle of the camera.
攝像頭的角度
Do you know that too?
這你也懂啊
That's great. I'll take you there.
那太好了 我帶你去
Let's go right at the moment.
現在就去
There are indeed some blind spots.
是有幾個死角啊
The immature young people
年輕的不懂事
always fight and bully people there.
總在那兒打架欺負人
Let's go. I'll show you.
走 我帶你去看看去
Let's go. This way.
走走走 這邊
Let's go.
走
It's so convenient to ask a favour from an acquaintance.
用自家人就是方便啊
You even came to check in the middle of the night.
半夜都能過來檢查
Did you married couple
你們夫妻
come here after work?
是下了班過來的嗎
We're not married.
我們不是夫妻
We are alumni.
我們是校友
When we were in school,
我們以前上學的時候
we always played around here.
老在這附近玩
So we dropped by here today.
今兒就說過來看看
It's done.
可以了
Please move this back to its original position.
麻煩您把這個搬回去
We're leaving first.
我們先走了
Okay, thank you.
好 謝謝啊
Wait.
等等
It hasn't changed at all.
一點都沒變
You haven't changed at all too.
你也一點都沒變
What did you say?
你說什麼
Nothing.
沒有
I heard you say something.
我聽見你說話來著
I said nothing.
什麼都沒說
Where are we going now?
我們現在回哪兒
The garage?
修車廠
I'll take you to Meng Xiaoshan's house.
送你去孟小杉家
I'm afraid my dad is still in the garage.
我怕我爸還在
He'll make a scene.
鬧挺
You can sleep well in Meng's house.
去孟家你還能睡個好覺
Does your dad still hurt you?
現在你爸還對你動手嗎
He doesn't dare to do it now.
他現在不敢
Next time when you come,
下次你來的時候
I'll ask them in advance
我提前問清楚
and try my best
儘量
not to let you meet my family.
不讓你碰到我的家人
You didn't say you were coming.
你沒說要來啊
Are you home?
到家沒
Look up.
抬頭
Do you want to go back to Qining
你想再跟我回齊寧
with me?
看一看嗎
Are you going back?
你要回去啊
I have to help Xiaonan get his household registration permit.
幫小楠回去拿戶口
Let them send it over will do.
那讓他們寄過來唄
This matter is complicated.
這個事比較複雜
I'll explain further to you tomorrow.
明天細說
Do you want to go?
想去嗎
Do you really want to go back?
你很想回去啊
From my perspective,
齊寧對我來講
Qining is my second hometown.
像是第二個故鄉
Last time,
上一次我們倆
we had a dispute.
鬧得不高興
I didn't have the chance to show you around.
沒帶你到處去看看
This time, I want to take you
想著這一次回去
to see the snowfield,
帶你去看看雪原
sunset, forest,
日落 樹林
and people in the past.
還有過去的人
My working hours are flexible.
我的工作時間很自由
As long as I have my phone and an Internet connection,
有手機和網絡就可以
I can leave anytime.
隨時能走
I'll book a schedule.
我去定行程
Okay.
好
Have an early night.
早點睡
I'm really leaving.
真走了
I just helped Qin Feng
我剛幫秦楓
to fix the surveillance of his billiard hall.
修好他檯球廳的監控
I remember
我記得
the CCTV in my brother-in-law's school
姐夫學校裡的監控
is also this brand.
也是這個牌子
If there's any problem,
如果有什麼問題的話
he may come to me.
你讓他找我
Thank you.
謝謝啊
Why are you bother thanking me?
你跟我還說謝
I said it on behalf of your brother-in-law.
替你姐夫說的
Recently, he's always worried that
他最近總是擔心
if the CCTV has malfunctioned,
學校攝像頭哪天壞了
the students facing danger in the blind spot will not be noticeable.
怕有死角學生出危險
Luckily, you're back.
幸好你回來了
Otherwise,
要不然他今晚
he can't sleep well again tonight.
又該睡不著覺
Pork rib soup.
排骨湯
Take it back for the kid.
帶回去給小孩喝
Your friend asked us to take care of him.
人家養在咱們家
We can't starve him.
可不能餓瘦了
Or else, we would disappoint his parents.
該對不起人家爸媽了
Okay, go in quickly.
行 快進去吧
Okay.
好
My brother-in-law has been waiting for you.
姐夫等半天了
Drive slowly.
那你慢點開啊
Okay.
知道
Where's Aunt Gui Xiao?
歸曉阿姨呢
She's staying with her friend.
去朋友家住了
What?
幹嘛
I'm waiting for her.
我還等著她呢
I need to go back to Qining.
我要回齊寧一趟
Is there anything
有什麼
you want me to bring to your dad?
要我幫你帶給你爸的
Or is there anything
還是有什麼
you want me to bring back for you?
要幫你帶回來的
You have just progressed a little
你們剛有一點點進展
but now you're leaving?
你就要走啊
Why do you always worry about me?
你怎麼總操心我的事
Mind your words.
注意措辭
I'm worried that
我是擔心
Aunt Gui Xiao is too outstanding.
歸曉阿姨那麼優秀
I'm afraid that when you return,
我怕你到時候
you can't get her back anymore.
追不回來歸曉阿姨
She'll go back with me.
她跟我一起回去
No one is taking care of you lately.
最近沒有人照顧你了
Be careful.
自己當心一點
Don't slack off on your homework.
功課也不能懈怠
Make it clear before you leave.
你先說清楚 說完再走
I'm going to take a shower.
我去洗個澡
Have the pork rib soup.
排骨湯喝了
I'm worried that
我是擔心
Aunt Gui Xiao is too outstanding.
歸曉阿姨那麼優秀
I'm afraid that when you return,
我怕你到時候
you can't get her back anymore.
追不回來歸曉阿姨
Your dad always makes a scene when he is drunk.
你爸一喝多就鬧
No one can deal with him.
誰都管不住
Don't go home tonight.
你今天就別回家睡了
Lu Chen.
路晨
He's your dad.
他可是你親爸
Don't take it to heart.
你別往心裡去
It's okay.
沒事
As long as he doesn't
他只要不把我姐
kick my sister out, I'll be fine.
趕出去就行
I'm going on a road trip.
這次是自駕遊
Sometimes the signal will be bad.
有時候可能信號不好
If you need anything,
你要有什麼事呢
just email me.
就跟我發郵件
When the signal gets better,
等信號好一點了
I will give you a reply.
我就給你回過來
Why is your first love
你那個初戀
going back to Qining all of a sudden?
為什麼忽然回齊寧
After he graduated from university,
他大學畢業以後
he was assigned to Qining.
就分配在齊寧
He has lived there
在那兒生活了
for more than ten years.
有十多年了
It's kind of his second hometown.
算是他的第二故鄉吧
Maybe he wants to go back and have a look.
可能是想回去看看
What about Qin Xiaonan?
那秦小楠怎麼辦
Who will take care of him after you leave?
你們走了誰照顧他
You met the person before. It's Hai Dong.
你見過的 海東
It's him.
那個啊
He can't even
他不是連功課
tutor Xiaonan.
都輔導不了嗎
We'll be back in two weeks.
兩個星期就回來了
What about you leave it to me?
要不然交給我吧
You?
你
He can stay at my place which is near to his school.
住我那兒離他學校近
I'll take care of the kid for two weeks.
我幫你帶兩個星期孩子
I'm being serious.
我認真的
Now I finally admit that
現在我終於承認
you really like kids.
你是真的喜歡小孩了
Why would I lie to you?
我騙你幹嘛
My aunt's kids
我阿姨家幾個小毛頭
like to play with me a lot on weekends.
週末最喜歡跟著我玩了
Leave it to me. It's a deal.
交給我 說好了啊
Give me his dad's contact information.
你把他爸聯繫方式給我
Just in case.
以防萬一
If I can't find you,
我要是找不到你們
I'll go to his dad.
直接找他爸
Okay, I'll share his phone number with you.
行 我給你發他電話
Qin Mingyu.
秦明宇
He has a nice name.
名字不錯
Tonight,
晚上
ask the kid to pack up his things.
你讓小孩收拾好東西
I'll call a taxi and fetch him to my house.
我叫個車 直接去我家
Thanks.
謝了
Bye.
走了
Safe journey.
注意安全啊
Ms Meng.
孟姐 孟姐
Is there any private room left?
還有包廂嗎
Yes, I'll find one for you.
有 我給你找
-Okay. I'll wait for you here. -Noted.
行 我在這兒等你啊
Gui Xiao.
歸曉
Are you going on a long journey again?
又要出遠門
Is Lu Chen here?
路晨來了嗎
Soon.
快了
Is Chen back too?
晨哥也回來了
Chen.
晨哥
I bought some fruit. We can eat them on the way.
買了點水果 路上吃
You're here.
來了
It's bumpy on the road.
路上顛
It'll be more convenient if you carry a bag instead of a suitcase.
換個行李袋方便一點
I have a bag here. You may use it.
我這兒有 換吧
I'll change to the bag inside.
那我進去換一下
I'll carry it for you.
我幫你拎過去
Gui Xiao.
歸曉
I still want to say something.
有句話我還是想說
Lu Chen was thoughtless.
這事路晨欠考慮了
You two just made up not long ago.
你們倆才剛和好多久啊
But now you are going on a trip together.
就單獨出去了
If you get pregnant these days,
兩人十幾天
it would be very troublesome.
鬧出人命多麻煩啊
Did you buy a new car?
新買的車
No, second-hand.
沒有 二手的
I've modified it after the repairs.
修了修 改裝了一下
Not bad.
真不錯
You modified a car worth one hundred  thousand yuan
十幾萬的車被你改成了
to be one that worth hundreds of thousands.
幾十萬的感覺
Awesome.
可以啊
Think carefully.
你可想清楚啊
If you don't want to
你要不想
get married so early,
定下這麼早結婚
you should take some protection measures.
就採取點保護措施
Don't get dizzy
你別一高興
and have a child on the spur of the moment.
被孩子拴住了
By then,
到時候又覺得
even if you feel you two are no more suitable
兩人那麼多年沒在一起
after those years of separation,
不合拍
it would be very troublesome to break up.
想分手你都麻煩
Fasten your seat belt.
安全帶繫上
We're leaving.
我們走了
Drive safely.
慢點開啊
You said
你又說了什麼
something you shouldn't have said, didn't you?
不該說的了吧
I'm afraid Gui Xiao is muddleheaded.
怕歸曉犯傻
Let's take a break.
休息一下
The next service area is quite far.
下個服務區挺遠的
Hot coffee.
熱咖啡
The food inside
我看裡邊那些吃的
didn't seem to be delicious.
也不太好吃
So I didn't buy any.
我就沒買
Don't we have GPS?
咱不是有導航嗎
I'm used to looking at the map.
看地圖看習慣了
I came here once last year.
去年來過一次
The scenery I can see along the way,
沿途能看到什麼風景
the location where the blacktop of the road was faded,
哪裡的柏油路面脫落
and the axle smashed by a truck,
哪裡有大車軋過的車軸
I still remember them.
我差不多都還有印象
There are some things that can't be navigated through GPS.
有些東西導航不出來
Here.
來
I just remembered something.
突然想起個事
Do you remember the man
你還記得在機場
we saw at the airport?
看到的那男的嗎
His name is Xu Yao.
他叫許曜
Don't you like meat floss?
你不愛吃肉鬆啊
You like meat floss.
我看你愛吃肉鬆
And I'm not picky. So I'll just eat this.
我不挑 吃這個就行
You're very observant.
觀察力不錯
His wife is seriously ill.
他老婆生重病了
The local hospital confirmed that
國內醫院確診說
she had to be operated on her spine.
要開刀動脊椎
It seems to be the back of the neck.
好像就是後脖子那塊
But after the surgery,
但是這個手術做下來
she will face dreadful sequela.
後遺症無窮
They dare not do it easily.
他們不太敢輕易去做
So they want to go overseas for another check-up.
就想出去再查查
If there is a certain possibility
如果有一定機率
to diagnosing
能診斷出是
another kind of tumour,
另一種性質的腫瘤
she doesn't need surgery,
那就不用手術
but radiotherapy.
放療就可以
His wife has been sick for many years.
這病也看了很多年了
He doesn't have much savings left.
他也沒什麼積蓄了
So he came to me.
就來找我
I saved some for myself.
我給自己留了一些
It's enough for the living expenses
夠我和秦小楠的
of Qin Xiaonan and me.
日常開銷
I gave him the rest.
其餘的我就都給他了
You're still in debt.
你還欠著外債呢
Just leave Qin Xiaonan to me.
秦小楠就交給我
He doesn't spend much anyway.
反正他的開銷也不大
No need.
不用
Qin Mingyu always pays his living expenses to me.
秦明宇會給我生活費的
Xu Yao and his wife
許曜跟他老婆
have known each other since childhood.
從小就認識
They've been tangled for many years.
分分合合好多年了
Probably the year before last.
大概是在前年
His wife got sick.
他老婆生的病
And they keep visiting the doctor since then.
之後就一直在看病
At that moment, they haven't gotten married yet.
那時候他們還沒有結婚
His wife disagreed to get a marriage certificate.
他老婆就不肯領證
She didn't want to weigh him down.
怕拖累他
But Xu Yao
許曜呢
held a wedding ceremony for her
就給她辦了一場婚禮
and insisted on marrying her.
死活都要娶人家
Life is so unpredictable.
人生多無常啊
The previous year, you were still happy with the achievements
上一年還春風得意
but fell into the mud pit the next year.
下一年就摔進了泥坑
It couldn't be when Xu Yao's wife was sick,
你說難道他老婆生病
he just abandoned her.
許曜就不要她了
And those who have been married.
還有那些結過婚的
After getting married,
婚後
if anyone has a career crisis,
誰要是出現事業危機
they would overcome it together.
那還不是得一起扛過去
Everyone faces ups and downs
誰的人生
in their lives.
沒有一道坎兒啊
You can't hope for your lover
總不能自己摔了
to support you selflessly
就希望自己的愛人
when you are facing difficulty,
無私地支持自己
but then
自己順風順水呢
you yourself find a better person
就找一個
when you have achieved a great success.
更一帆風順的人
This is not reality.
這不是現實
It's imagination.
是想像
Meng Xiaoshan cares about me.
孟小杉為我著想
Don't mind what she said.
說的話不要放在心上
Meng Xiaoshan
孟小杉
doesn't have a clear understanding about
也不是完全瞭解
my situation.
我的狀況
At most, only two years.
最多兩年
I will settle my debt.
賬就平了
Then I'll save money to marry you.
再攢錢娶你
You wish!
想得美
Are you not willing to marry me?
不讓娶
If you agree,
讓呢
we'll sleep in the same room tonight.
今晚就睡一個房間
If you don't agree, we'll sleep separately.
不讓呢 就分開睡
The room we booked yesterday
我們昨天訂的酒店
has a double bed.
雙人床
Captain Lu.
路隊
How have you been these two years?
怎麼樣 這兩年好嗎
Good.
挺好的
This is...
這位是
Gui Xiao, my girlfriend.
歸曉 我女朋友
Hello.
你好
Hello, I'm Sun Hao.
嫂子好 我是孫浩
Captain Lu.
路隊
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你怎麼不早說
If you told me earlier,
早說
I would have arranged for a deluxe couple package
我就給你弄一個
for you.
情侶豪華套
Do you still have this kind of service?
你這兒還有這個
It's for vacation.
度假的嘛
Of course we have suites for couples.
情侶套房當然得有了
Why are you taking me here?
你說你來這兒幹嘛
It's cold.
多冷啊
Hang in there.
忍一忍
The sunrise will be beautiful tomorrow morning.
明天早上日出特別美
Trust me.
相信我
Let me do it.
我來 我來
You came at the right time.
你們來得正是時候
Winter is not the peak season.
冬天不是旺季
There are fewer people staying here.
住的人少
Look,
就這一片
during the summer,
夏天
it is an endless prairie.
是一望無際的大草原
We simply followed
我們就照著
the design of a Mongolian yurt
蒙古包的樣子
and built a resort.
建了個度假村
Thank you.
謝謝
Xiao,
嫂子
Actually, I'm not
其實我不是
in Captain Lu's team.
路隊他們隊上的
I'm not qualified.
我不夠格
They are
他們隊上
all elites.
都是菁英中的菁英
But Captain Lu taught us how to dismantle bombs.
不過路隊教過我們拆彈
He's my master.
算是我師父
Do you know how I felt
你知道我第一次見路隊
when I first met Captain Lu?
什麼感覺嗎
He's so arrogant.
太拽了
The first time I saw him
我第一次見他
standing there,
往那兒一站
the first sentence he said was,
第一句話就是
"It's not easy to be a SWAT."
特警是沒那麼好當的
He scared us on the first day
第一天就嚇唬我們
saying that there is no absolute expert in dismantling bombs.
說拆彈沒有絕對的專家
Everyone is just risking their lives.
就是頭往褲腰帶上掖
Well,
這不
the EOD expert,
去年剛跟他交流的
who had a communication with him last year,
國外那個拆彈專家
was just killed in the war zone.
剛在戰區被炸死
When I first learned it,
我第一次學的時候
I was very careful.
特別小心謹慎
I thought I was successful.
以為自己行了
So I cut it off.
咔嚓那麼一剪
And then he came.
後面就被他來了一下
Do you know what Captain Lu said?
你知道路隊說什麼嗎
What?
什麼
He said I was already blown to death.
說你被炸死了
Before Captain Lu left...
路隊走之前
Alright.
好了
Let's not talk about the past.
不說過去
How can I not?
過去怎麼能不說呢
That was all your heroic deeds.
那全是你的英勇事蹟啊
Xiao.
嫂子
When Captain Lu
路隊這兒
covered for others,
掩護下邊人的時候
he was shot.
中過彈
You should have seen the scar.
嫂子早該見過了
Captain Lu.
路隊
The third one from this side.
從這邊拐過去第三個
I have to help my mom with the account.
我還要幫我媽算賬
Captain Lu.
路隊
The horses are all here.
馬全在這兒了
Pick one if you want.
你要想騎的話自己挑
I'll go back first.
我就先回去了
It's all dark.
都是暗的
They slept so early.
他們睡得這麼早啊
It's late.
不早了
It's already eleven.
已經十一點了
How many beds are in there?
這裡邊幾張床
May I?
行嗎
You kissed me that time
當初親我
without asking.
又沒問
It was normal when I was injured.
帶傷正常
Aren't you an EOD technician?
你不是排爆嗎
EOD is my major.
排爆是專業方向
The duty of SWAT
特警最本職的工作
is to maintain the stability of our country.
是維護國家的安定
Whether it's a gunfight, knife battle,
槍戰 刀戰
or bomb, I've encountered it all.
炸彈我都遇到過
You didn't mention it before.
之前你都沒說過
What's there to say?
有什麼好說的
On the first day I went in,
我第一天進去
the old captain told me
老隊長就告訴我
there were things
有些話
you shouldn't tell your family
能不告訴家屬
and you'd better not.
最好不要說
It has no benefits
除了擔心
except to worry them.
沒好處
All these years in the SWAT,
特警這些年
none of us was uninjured.
沒有一個是不掛彩的
Last year,
去年有一個
a new kid
新來的小朋友
hurt his leg during training.
受訓的時候摔傷了腿
He was quite happy.
還挺高興
He said,
揚言
finally, he was injured
終是受了傷
and dared to say
敢坦蕩蕩地說
that he belonged to the squadron.
自己是這個中隊的人了
You insisted on going.
當初你非要去
You didn't listen to any of my advice.
說什麼你都不聽
Now you've suffered so much.
受了這麼多苦
This is crazy.
真是瘋了
Why do you have to come to the prairie in winter?
大冬天的非要來草原玩
People usually come in summer.
人家都是夏天來
It's freezing all night.
凍了一晚上
I am frozen to death.
簡直要凍死了
The craziest thing is
最神經病的是呢
watching the sunrise.
看日出
Sunrise my ass.
日出個鬼啊你
I'm going to sleep with Sun Hao.
我去和孫浩睡
Calm down.
你不要生氣了
We've been frozen all night.
都凍了一晚上了
Why are you still watching the sunrise?
還看什麼日出啊
Okay, go on.
好 你們繼續
All right.
好了 好了 好了
It's all your fault.
都是你
Did you just quarrel with your girlfriend?
跟嫂子吵架了
Besides this,
除了這個
I can't think of anything else.
我也想不出來其他的了
Your girlfriend is still
老婆還在
lying on her warm bed.
熱炕頭上躺著呢
What can you do coming out
一個大男人
in the middle of the night?
半夜出來能幹什麼呀
Go that way. It's spacious.
往那邊去 寬闊
Wait for me.
等等我呀
Last time when we came here,
上次我們來的時候
his wife was still here.
他老婆還在
Now, she's gone.
現在人已經走了
He's left alone.
就剩他自己一個人了
Let me knock on the door.
我去敲門
He has said it many times.
他說了好多次了
When you return,
等你回來了
he wants to have a drink with you.
一定好好跟你喝一杯
It's too late.
太晚了
The light is still on.
你沒看燈還亮著呢
The guest-welcoming light is on
迎客燈在
means that the host hasn't slept yet.
主家就還沒睡
Who is it?
誰呀
Good evening.
晚上好
Why are you here today?
今天你怎麼來了
Captain Lu.
路隊
Come on.
來 來 來
Here, take it.
來 拿著
Sit down.
坐下 坐下
I made it myself.
我自己做的
Have a taste.
嚐一嚐啊 來
Come on.
來 來
Drink.
喝 喝
The last time we met was...
上次見面是
Two years ago.
兩年前
Yes.
對 對 對
Is Captain Lu still in Qining?
路隊還在齊寧嗎
I went back to my hometown.
回故鄉了
Okay.
好 好 好
You've reached the age.
到年紀了
It's good to be with your parents.
在父母身邊好
Here.
來
Let's eat.
吃吧
You're drinking too fast.
你也喝得太快了
Here.
來
Captain Lu.
路隊
I wish you leave a few days later.
你要是晚走幾天就好了
My youngest son is coming back.
我那小兒子就回來了
Next time.
下次
When he goes to Beijing next time,
下次他去北京
ask him to come to me.
讓他去找我
Okay.
好 好
Actually, when I heard about
其實當年第一次聽到
your family situation at first,
你們這樣的家庭
I was quite shocked.
挺驚訝的
What for?
有什麼驚訝的
There are over 20 police officers in a family.
一家子二十多個警察
It is heroic to say,
說起來是英雄
but difficult to do.
做起來挺難的
Outsiders don't understand.
外人不理解
We, as your peers, know that
我們這些同行最懂
the family glory
家族榮耀這四個字
is paid for with blood and tears.
是用血淚換回來的
Family glory.
家族榮耀
Captain Lu.
路隊
Thank you.
謝謝你
My stepfather
我繼父
was also a person who defended the country.
也是一個保衛國家的人
He married my mother for only a few years
和我母親結婚沒幾年
and died of illness after that.
生病去世了
I had his influence
我做這一行
in getting into this career.
有他的影響
I had no goal when I was studying.
讀書的時候一直沒目標
I came here after graduation.
畢業後來了這裡
In the frontline of the police force,
在警隊的一線裡
I have arrested
追捕過
the most vicious fugitives
最窮凶極惡的逃犯
and dismantled thousands of
拆過上千個
bombs, professional or non-professional.
專業不專業的炸彈
I think
我才覺得
this is the best way to live.
這樣活著是最好的
That's why I envy you.
所以說羨慕你們
With the guidance of your parents,
有父輩的引導
you've avoided many detours.
少走了不少彎路
Is something bothering you today?
你今天有心事啊
People always have something on their minds.
人活著總會有心事
Sometimes more,
有時候多
sometimes less.
有時候少
Have you visited your former captain?
去看你們老隊長了嗎
The day after tomorrow.
後天
I'll go on my way back.
走的時候去
Also, I'll visit some old friends.
順便再看看幾個老朋友
Have some warm milk tea to warm up your body.
喝點熱乎奶茶暖暖身子
Not bad, right?
還可以吧
What were you talking about with Mama Sun?
跟孫媽媽聊什麼呢
She said the couple yesterday
她說昨天那對小夫妻
was frozen
被凍得不行
and had a big fight.
大吵了一架
They didn't even see the sunrise this morning.
今天早上連日出都沒看
They just went straight to the city.
直接去市區了
It's really cold.
是很冷
And the more I sleep, the colder I get.
而且越睡越冷
I just woke up from the cold
我就是被凍醒了
and I found you...
才發現你
Do you know what this is called?
知道這叫什麼嗎
What?
什麼
The sunlight in the morning (Chen Xiao in Pinyin).
晨曉
Don't you think we're destined to be together?
你覺不覺得我們特有緣
How can you tell?
怎麼看出來的
Look.
你看
The last word
你的名字
of your name is Chen.
最後一個字是晨
Mine is Xiao.
我是曉
Chen Xiao.
晨曉
It means the sunlight in the morning.
早晨的日光
Isn't it perfect?
很配吧
Have some milk tea.
喝點奶茶
Thank you.
謝謝
After that couple left,
等那一對小夫妻一走
you are indeed
你們就是名副其實的
the only privileged guests.
唯一貴客了
You guys talk.
你們聊
Come in.
來 進
This is a senior apartment.
我們這老年公寓啊
We have the most convenient transportation.
這交通啊是最方便的
And the location is good
而且二環內呢
in the second ring.
地理位置特別好
Friendship Hospital
這個友誼醫院呢
is right in front of us.
就在我們跟前
There are gym and entertainment rooms.
有健身房 娛樂間
It's totally a hotel apartment.
完全酒店公寓啊
The rooms are in a suite...
房間配套
Yes.
是
My boss is calling. Sorry.
老闆電話 不好意思了
Go ahead. I'll look around by myself.
您忙 我自己逛一下
Okay.
好
How is this apartment?
這公寓怎麼樣
It's pretty good.
挺好的
We viewed five apartments this morning.
今天上午看了五家
Give a comment.
你點評一下
Me?
我點評
I want to know
看一下
your view as a kid.
你們小朋友的視角
Good.
挺好的
That's all?
沒了
You lack words in the expression.
言語匱乏啊
I'll get you more language classes after this.
回頭給你補補語文
Aunt Duan Rou.
段柔阿姨
Why are we viewing
為什麼我們一直在看
the senior apartment?
老年公寓啊
It's a long story.
說來話長
How about I treat you to a nice meal?
帶你吃頓好的去
Let's go.
走
I'm also from a single-parent family.
我也是單親家庭的
Just like you.
和你一樣
My mum
我媽媽呢
is not in good health recently.
最近身體不是很好
But I often go on business trips
但是我經常出差
and don't have time to take care of her.
沒有時間照顧她
So I am thinking of
就想給她找一個
arranging for a senior apartment for her.
高階的老年公寓
There are doctors
這樣有醫生
and others taking care of her.
有人照顧她
There are also new friends to play with her.
還有新朋友陪她一起玩
After finding a few,
找了幾家以後吧
I suddenly became interested
忽然就對這個行業
in this industry,
感興趣
and started investing.
就開始投資了
Didn't your father look for you?
你爸爸都不找你的嗎
He's busy.
他忙
After Uncle Lu left,
路叔叔走了以後
he will be
他就是
the captain of the SWAT brigade.
特警大隊的隊長了
Is it delicious?
好吃嗎
Yes.
好吃
One more?
再來一個
Come on.
來
Thank you.
謝謝 謝謝
Here, eat.
來 吃
Make yourself at home.
別客氣啊
Have another bun.
再吃個饢
Thank you.
謝謝 謝謝
The people here
他們這兒的人
are really enthusiastic.
真的好熱情啊
Last time when I came with Cai Yaya,
上次我跟蔡雅雅來
we met a family on the way
我們在路上遇到一戶
that we didn't even know.
根本就不認識的人家
We just wanted to ask for directions,
我們就只是想問個路
but they pulled us into their house
直接把我們拉進去
and gave us a bowl of milk tea
塞了一碗奶茶
and some beef jerky.
還有幾把牛肉乾
We were both dumbfounded.
整得我倆都傻了
Change the channel to CCTV and watch the news.
換中央台看新聞
I have a call.
接個電話
I need to answer a call.
我去接個電話
Hello, who is this?
您好 哪位
I'm Gui Yuanshan,
我是歸遠山
the father of Gui Xiao.
歸曉的父親
You remember me, right?
你應該還記得吧